I was sitting with my girls,
كنت جالسة مع فتياتي،
and Joy said,
و قالت جوي،
"Dang, I wish he'd get off my back.
يا الله ، يا ليته يتركني لحالي.
My daddy, he calls me all the time."
أبي ،إنه يتصل بي باستمرار."
"Lucky for you he calls at all," said Jasmine.
" يا لحظك إنه يتصل بك دائما"، قالت جاسمن.
"I haven't heard from my dad in years."
"لم اسمع شيئا عن والدي منذ سنوات."
At this moment, I knew the girls needed a way
في تلك اللحظة علمت ، أن الفتيات يحتاجون إيجاد طريقة
to connect with their fathers.
للتواصل مع آبائهم.
At Camp Diva, my non-profit organization,
في مخيم ديفا، منظمتي الغير ربحية،
we have these types of conversations all the time
نجري مثل هذه المحادثات باستمرار
as a way to help girls of African descent
لمساعدة الفتيات من أصول افريقية،
prepare for their passage into womanhood.
الإستعداد للإنتقال من عالم الطفولة إلى حياة النساء.
These girls just needed
هؤلاء الفتيات يحتجن
a way to invite their fathers into their lives
طريقة لدعوة آبائهم إلى حياتهم،
on their own terms.
بالطريقة التي تناسبهم.
So I asked the girls,
لذا سألت الفتيات،
"How can we help other girls
" كيف نستطيع مساعدة الفتيات الأخريات
develop healthy relationships with their fathers?"
أن يطوروا علاقات سليمة مع آبائهم؟"
"Let's have a dance," one girl shouted,
" لنقم حفلة راقصة،" قالت إحدى الفتيات،
and all the girls quickly backed her up.
ووافق كل الفتيات الأخريات.
They started dreaming about the decorations,
و بدأوا يحلمون عن تزيين مكان الحفلة،
invitations, the dresses they were going to wear,
الدعوات ، الفساتين التي سوف يرتدينها،
and what their fathers could and could not wear. (Laughter)
و ما هو مسموح لآبائهم بارتدائة و ما هو غير مسموح. (ضحك)
It was off and running before I could even blink my eyes,
و كانت كل التفاصيل تظهر ، قبل أن يرتد إلىّ طرفي
but even if I could have slowed down those girls,
و لكن حتى لو كنت استطيع أن اهدئ من سرعة الفتيات ،
I wouldn't have,
لما فعلت ذلك،
because one thing that I have learned
لأني تعلمت شيئا واحداً مهماً
from over a decade of working with girls
من عقَد من الزمان من العمل مع الفتيات
is that they already know what they need.
و هو أنهم يعلمون ما يحتاجون إليه.
The wisdom lives inside of them.
إن الحكمة موجودة بداخلهم.
As long as they have infrastructure,
طالما يملكون البنية الأساسية
mentorship and resources,
الإرشاد و الموارد،
they can build what they need,
يستطيعون بناء ما يحتاجون،
not only to survive, but to thrive.
ليس فقط من أجل البقاء ، ولكن من أجل الإزدهار.
So we had a dance,
لذا أقمنا حفلة راقصة،
and girls and their fathers came in multitudes.
و جاءت الفتيات و آبائهم بأعداد مضاعفة.
They were dressed to the nines.
كانوا في كامل أناقتهم.
They acted sweet.
و تعاملوا بلباقة.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
They acted silly.
و كانوا مرحين.
They really enjoyed each other's company.
و استمتعوا بصحبة بعضهم.
It was a huge success.
لقد نجحت الفكرة نجاحا مدوياً.
And the girls decided to make it an annual event.
و قررت الفتيات ، أن يجعلوا الحدث سنوياً.
So as the seasons changed,
و مع تبدل الفصول،
and it was time to plan the dance again,
جاءت مواعيد التجهيز للحفلة الراقصة مرة أخرى،
one girl named Brianna spoke up,
تشجعت إحدى الفتيات و تدعى بريانا،
and she said,
و قالت،
"My dad can't come to the dance,
" والدي لا يستطيع أن يحضر الحفلة الراقصة،
and this whole thing is making me sad."
و هذا الأمر كله يجعلني أشعر بالحزن."
"Why not?" the girls asked.
" لماذا؟ " سألت الفتيات.
"Because he's in jail," she bravely admitted.
" لأنه بالسجن " اعترفت بشجاعة.
"Well, can he just get out for a day?" one of the girls asked. (Laughter)
" ألا يستطيعون اخراجه يوما واحدا فقط؟ " تساءلت احدى الفتيات. ( ضحك)
"And come in shackles?
" ويأتي في قيوده؟
That's worse than not having him here at all."
هذا أسوأ من ألا يأتي على الإطلاق."
At this moment, I saw an opportunity
في هذه اللحظة رأيت فرصة
for the girls to rise to the occasion
للفتيات ليكونوا على مستوى الحدث
and to become their own heroes.
و ليصبحوا بطلات في نظر أنفسهن.
So I asked, "What do you think we should do about this?
و سألتهم ، " ماذا تظنون أننا يجب أن نفعل إزاء هذا الأمر؟ "
We want every girl to experience the dance, right?"
نريد أن تحضر كل الفتيات الحفل الراقص ، صحيح ؟ "
So the girls thought for a moment,
و فكرت الفتيات للحظة،
and one girl suggested,
اقترحت احدى الفتيات،
"Why don't we just take the dance in the jail?"
لما لا نقيم الحفلة الراقصة في السجن ؟"
Most of the girls doubted the possibility of that,
معظم الفتيات شككوا في إحتمالية حدوث ما قالت،
and said, "Are you crazy?
و قالوا لها ،" هل جننت ؟
Who is going to allow a bunch of little girls,
من سيسمح لمجموعة من البنات،
dressed up — " (Laughter)
المتأنقات - "( ضحك)
" — to come inside a jail and dance with their daddies in Spongebob suits?"
" - أن يدخلوا السجن و يرقصوا مع آبائهم في بذات سبونج بوب؟ "
Because that's what they called them.
لأن هذا ما كانوا يدعون زي السجن.
I said, "Girls, well, well,
قلت ، " حسن، حسن يا فتيات ،
you never know unless you ask."
لن تعرفوا حتى تسألوا."
So a letter was written to the Richmond City Sheriff,
لذا تم كتابة خطاب لنقيب شرطة مدينة ريتشموند،
signed collectively by each girl,
و تم توقيعه من كل الفتيات،
and I would have to say, he is a very special sheriff.
و يجب أن أشير ، إلى أنه نقيب شرطة مميز للغاية.
He contacted me immediately and said,
اتصل بي فوراً وقال،
whenever there is an opportunity to bring families inside,
حيثما توجد فرصة ، لدخول العائلات إلى ذويهم داخل السجن،
his doors are always open.
فإن أبوابه مفتوحة دوماً.
Because one thing he did know,
لأنه كان يعلم شيئاً مؤكداً،
that when fathers are connected to their children,
عندما يحدث تواصل بين الآباء و أبنائهم ،
it is less likely that they will return.
لن يعود الآباء مرة أخرى إلى السجن.
So,
لذلك،
16 inmates and 18 girls were invited.
تم دعوة 16 سجين و 18 فتاة.
The girls were dressed in their Sunday best,
كانت الفتيات في كامل أناقتهن ، في أزياء يوم الأحد،
and the fathers traded in their yellow and blue jumpsuits
و الآباء استبدلوا بذاتهم الصفراء و الزرقاء
for shirts and ties.
بقمصان و ربطات عنق.
They hugged.
تبادلوا الأحضان.
They shared a full catered meal of chicken and fish.
و استمتعوا بوجبة دسمة من السمك و الدجاج.
They laughed together.
ضحكوا مع بعضهم البعض.
It was beautiful.
كان ذلك جميلاً.
The fathers and daughters even experienced
حتى أن الآباء و بناتهم حصلوا
an opportunity to have a physical connection,
على فرصة للقرب المكاني من بناتهم،
something that a lot of them didn't even have
و هذا شئ لم يحصل عليه الكثير منهم
for a while.
منذ فترة طويلة.
Fathers were in a space where they were able to
استطاع الآباء
make their daughter's plate,
أن يلعبوا مع بناتهم،
and pull out her chair and extend his hand for a dance.
و بلباقة كانوا يقومون بتقديم الكرسي لهن و طلب الرقصة منهن.
Even the guards cried.
حتى الحراس بكوا.
But after the dance,
لكن بعد انتهاء الحفلة الراقصة،
we all realized that Dad still would be in jail.
ادركنا أن الآباء ما زالوا داخل أسوار السجن.
So we needed to create something
لذا احتجنا أن نصنع شيئا
that they could take with them.
يستطيعون أخذه معهم.
So we brought in Flip cams,
لذا احضرنا كاميرات فليب " ماركة معروفة لكاميرات فيديو صغيرة"
and we had them look at the Flip cams
و جعلناهم ينظرون إلى كاميرات فليب
and just interview each other --
و يجرون مقابلات مع بعضهم بعض--
their messages, their thoughts.
رسائلهم ، و أفكارهم.
This was going to be used as a touchstone
لتكون لهم كنوع من الذكري
so when they started to miss each other
عندما يبدأون الإشتياق لبعضهم البعض
and feel disconnected,
و يشعرون بغياب التواصل مع بناتهم
they could reconnect through this image.
يمكنهم إعادة التواصل عبر هذه الصور.
I'll never forget that one girl looked in her father's eyes
لن أنسى كيف أن احدى الفتيات نظرت في عيني والدها
with that camera and said,
بتلك الكاميرا وقالت،
"Daddy, when you look at me, what do you see?"
" أبي ، عندما تنظر إلى، ماذا ترى؟ "
Because our daddies are our mirrors
لأن آباءنا هم مثل المرآة الخاصة بنا
that we reflect back on
التي نتأمل بها
when we decide about what type of man we deserve,
عندما نبحث عن نوع الرجال الذين يستحقوننا،
and how they see us for the rest of our lives.
و كيف ينظرون إلينا لبقية حياتنا.
I know that very well,
أعلم ذلك جيداً.
because I was one of the lucky girls.
لأنني كنت إحدى الفتيات المحظوظات.
I have had
كان لدي
my father in my life always.
والدي في حياتي دوماً.
He's even here today.
حتى أنه اليوم هنا معي.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
And that is why it is extremely special
و لهذا فإن هذا الأمر بغاية الأهمية
for me to make sure that these girls
بالنسبة لي ، للتأكد ان هؤلاء الفتيات
are connected to their fathers,
في حالة تواصل مع آبائهن.
especially those who are separated
خصوصا اولئك المنفصلين
because of barbed wires and metal doors.
بسبب الأسلاك الشائكة أو الأبواب المعدنية.
We have just created a form
لقد خلقنا صيغة
for girls who have heavy questions on their heart
للفتيات اللائي تدور الأسئلة الثقيلة في خاطرهن
to be in a position to ask their fathers those questions
ليتمكنوا من سؤال آبائهم
and given the fathers the freedom to answer.
و أن يملك الآباء حرية الإجابة.
Because we know that the fathers
لأننا نعلم ان الأباء
are even leaving with this one thought:
يغادرون بفكرة واحدة :
What type of woman am I preparing to put in the world?
أي نوع من النساء ستكون ابتني في هذا العالم ؟
Because a father is locked in
و لا يعني وجود الأب محبوساً بين أربعة جدران
does not mean he should be locked out
حبسه أيضاً
of his daughter's life.
عن حياة ابنته.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)